Jeff Martin

I am a passionate software developer bringing years of experience in high-scale web application development and architecture, creating excellent developer experiences, and cross-team collaboration.

I am proficient in Go, Typescript, shell, and Python, as well as web application architecture, CICD, testing, and developer platforms.

Experience

Jan 2017 -Aug 2023

Teachers Pay Teachers - Senior Software Engineer L4, Developer Tools

- Designed, implemented, and assisted the migration to a developer platform powering the vast majority of applications in production and used daily by the majority of the 100+ contributor engineering organization.
- Designed and built an autoscaling docker build cluster that powered most applications and CI workloads.
- Core contributor to backend stack in Elixir, including observability and error triage system, GraphQL layer for background jobs, CI suite.
- Contributed to company's open source projects, including plug_instrumenter and linux-audit-exporter, as well as an internal MySQL driver.

May 2014 -Sep 2015

Uservoice - Software Engineer, Frontend Lead

- Architected and built enterprise frontend application in Angularis.
- Introduced continuous integration pipeline.
- Implemented numerous Rest API endpoints in Go.

Aug 2010 -Aug 2013

MyLikes - Software Engineer

- Built an image-based social network in Python that reached the Alexa Top 100 ranking.
- Built a system to aggregate social media post stats for all MyLikes users.
- Built a twitter crawler which detected click rings and other forms of fraud.
- Supported ad pipeline ingesting hundreds of millions of clicks per day.

Education

Education

BA, International Political Studies; San Francisco State University

Spring 1 Batch, 2024; Recurse Center

• Built log server prototypes using the Linux io_uring subsystem.

Personal Projects

Open source Contributions & Talks

- Contributions to various projects including elixir-core, Poison, aerc, protocgen-jsonschema, and others.
- Spoke about Elixir in production at The Big Elixir, 2018.

jeffmartin@gmail.com • +1 408 410 7626 • github.com/jeffrom Portland, OR